Guide to the Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 4: Boxes 67-88
5583/1
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
120 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations. The materials issued by corporations include company histories, employee newsletters, employee benefit plans, personnel practice manuals, performance appraisal forms, affirmative action policies, training brochures, job descriptions, and career development programs as well as national trade association documents and recruitment material.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Several economic activities(sectors) are represented in the collection, such as manufacturing, transportation, mining, banking, insurance, utilities, trade, and services. Corporations whose pamphlets are held in the collection include AT&T, Bethlehem Steel, Bell Telephone System, Firestone Tire & Rubber, Ford Motor Co., General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, General Motors, Goodyear Tire & Rubber, Heinz, International Harvester, Johnson & Johnson, Lockheed Aircraft Co., Maytag Co., Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., National Association of Manufacturers, Pennsylvania Railroad Co., Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Standard Oil, Tennessee Valley Authority, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse Electric among numerous other corporations.
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into six sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-22
Section 2: Boxes 23-44
Section 3: Boxes 45-66
Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Section 5: Boxes 89-110
Section 6: Boxes 111-121
SUBJECTS
Names:
A. Philip Randolph Institute.; Abbott Laboratories.; Abbott Laboratories. House Organs.; Abraham & Straus.; Addressograph-Multigraph Corporation.; Administrative Management Society.; Adult Education Association.; Aero Supply Mfg. Co.; Aerojet-General Corporation.; Aeroquip Corporation.; Aerospace Industries Association of America.; Aetna Life Insurance Company (Hartford, Conn.); Affiliated Schools for Workers.; African- American Labor Center.; Agway Inc.; Air Reduction Company.; Air Transport Association of America.; Airlines Negotiating Committee.; Alaska. Department of Administration.Division of Personnel.; Alden's, Inc.; Alexander Smith & Sons, Carpet Co.; Allegheny Ludlum Steel Corporation.; Allegheny Metal.; Allied Chemical & Dye Corporation; Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company.; Aluminum Company of America.; American Arbitration Association.; American Brake Shoe Company.; American Can Company.; American Labor Education Service.; American Locomotive Company.; American Management Association.; American Merchant Marine Institute.; American Metal Climax, Inc.; American Motors Corporation.; American Petroleum Institute.; American Plan Association.; American Society of Safety Engineers.; American Telephone and Telegraph Company.; American Textile Manufacturers Institute.; American Thread Company.; American Trucking Associations.; American Type Founders Company.; American Vocational Association.; Americans Against Union Control of Government.; Amtrak.; Anaconda American Brass Company.; Anaconda Company.; Anaconda Copper Mining Company.; Anaconda Wire and Cable Company.; Anchor Hocking Glass Corporation.; Armco Steel Corporation.; Armour and Company.; Armstrong Cork Company.; Associated Builders & Contractors (U.S.); Associated General Contractors of America.; Association of American Railroads.; Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad Company.; Atlantic Refining Company.; Atlas Chemical Industries.; ATO, Inc.; Automobile Manufacturers Association.; Automotive and Aviation Parts Manufacturers.; Automotive Council for War Production.; Bell & Howell Co.; Bell Aircraft Corporation.; Bell of Pennsylvania.; Bell Telephone Company.; Bell Telephone Laboratories.; Bethlehem Steel Corporation.; Bird and Son, Inc.; Bituminous Coal Operators' Association.; Bloomer Brothers.; Boeing Aerospace Company.; Boeing Company.; Borden Company.; Brockway Glass Company.; Building Trades Employers' Association.; Bureau of National Affairs (Arlington, Va.); Burlington Industries, Inc.; Burndy Engineering Company.; Burrough Corporation.; California Institute of Technology. Industrial Relations Center.; California Institute of Technology.; California State Personnel Board.; Canadian National Railways; Canadian Pacific Railway Company.; Carborundum Company (Niagara Falls, N.Y.); Carnation Company.; Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation.; Carrier Corporation.; Caterpillar Tractor Company.; Celanese Corporation.; Central Hudson Gas and Electric Corporation.; Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America.; Chemical Corn Exchange Bank.; Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company of Maryland.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company of Virginia.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company.; Chessie System, inc.; Chicago Transit Authority.; Chrysler Corporation.; Cincinnati Bell Inc.; Civil Service Assembly of the United States and Canada.; Climax Molybdenum Company.; Clothing Manufacturers Association of the U.S.A.; Colgate-Palmolive Company.; Colorado Fuel and Iron Company.; Columbia Gas Company.; Commerce and Industry Association of New York.; Committee for the Nation's Health.; Commonwealth Edison Company.; Communications Workers of America.; Cone Mills Corporation.; Connecticut General Life Insurance Company.; Consolidated Edison Company of New York, inc.; Consolidated Gas, Electric Light, and Power Company of Baltimore.; Consolidated Natural Gas Company.; Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation.; Consumers' League of New York City.; Consumers Power Company (Mich.); Container Corporation of America.; Continental Can Company.; Continental Insurance Company.; Continental Oil Company.; Cooperative League of the U.S.A.; Corn Products Refining Company.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.; Cornell University.; Corning Glass Works.; Council Against Communist Aggression (U.S.); Council for International Progress in Management (USA); Council of Profit Sharing Industries (U.S.); Crane Co.; Crane Packing Co.; Credit Union National Association.; Crouse-Hinds Company.; Crown Zellerbach Corporation.; Crucible Steel Company of America.; Dan River Mills Inc.; Dartnell Corporation.; Daystrom, inc.; Dartnell Corporation.; Deere & Company.; Detroit Edison Company.; Diamond Alkali Company.; Dictaphone Corp.; Dole Food Company.; Douglas Aircraft Company.; Dow Chemical Company.; E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Company.; Eagle Pencil Company.; Eastern Gas and Fuel Associates.; Eastern Western & Southwestern Canier Company.; Eastman Kodak Company.; Eaton Corporation.; Eaton Manufacturing Company.; Ecusta Paper Company.; Electronic Industries Alliance.; Eli Lilly and Company.; Employers' Association of Chicago.; Employers' Association of Detroit.; Employers' Association of Grand Rapids.; Employers' Association of Massachusetts.; Employers' Association of Milwaukee.; Employers' Association of Pittsburgh.; Employers' Association of Washington.; Employers' Group of Insurance Companies.; Employers' Labor Relations Information Committee.; Employers' of Mutual of Wasau.; Engineers Joint Council. Engineering Manpower Commission.; Erie Railroad Company.; Erie-Lackawanna Railroad Company.; Erlanger Mills, Inc.; Erwin Cotton Mills.; Esso Research and Engineering Company.; Esso Standard Oil Company.; Exxon Corporation; Falstaff Brewing Corporation; Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America; Federal Professional Association (U.S.); Federal Reserve Bank of New York; Federated Employers of San Francisco; Federated Employers of the Bay Area; Fieldcrest Mills Inc.; William Filene's Sons Co.; Firestone Tire and Rubber Company; First National Bank (Ithaca, N.Y.); First National Bank Maryland; First National Bank of Boston; First National Bank of Chicago; First National Bank of Portland (Portland, Me.); First National Bank of St. Louis; First Pennsylvania Bank, N.A.; First Pennsylvania Banking and Trust Company, Philadelphia.; Fischer and Porter Company; Florida Power & Light Company; Ford Foundation; Ford Motor Company; Foster and Forbes Glass Company; Foundation for Economic Education, inc.; General Dynamics Corporation.; General Electric Company; George Fischer, Ltd.; J.N. Adam & Company.; New Jersey Bell Telephone Company.; New York Chamber of Commerce.; Society for Equitable Assurances on Lives and Survivorships.; South Central Bell.; University of California, Berkeley. Institute of Industrial Relations.; William Filene's Sons Co.; Commonwealth Edison Company; A. Philip Randolph Institute; ATO, Inc.; Aero Supply Mfg. Co.; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
Subjects:
Adult education; Aeronautics; Agricultural industries; Aluminum industry and trade; Airlines; Aircraft industry; Agricultural machinery; Architectural metal-work; Audio equipment industry; Automobile industry and trade; Arbitration, Industrial; Agricultural chemicals industry; Audio equipment industry; Bituminous materials industry; Building trades; Buildings--Environmental engineering; Banks and banking; Breweries; Baked products industry; Business consultants; Clothing trade; Coal mines and mining; Chemical industry; Compressor industry; Clerks (Retail trade); Computer industry; Cereal products; Consumer protection; Container industry; Credit unions; Clay industries; Cement industries; Copper alloys; Dairy products industry; Detergent industry; Executives--Training of; Electric power transmission; Electronics industries; Food industry and trade; Frozen foods and industry; Footwear industry; Fruit trade; Farm produce--Marketing--Government policy; Finance, Public; Glass container industry; Glass manufacture; Gas extraction; Grain trade; Grocery trade; Gasket industry; Human capital; Hydroelectric power plants; Life insurance.; Iron industry and trade; Property insurance.; Casualty insurance.; Instructional materials industry; Health insurance.; Investment banking; Infant formula industry; Knit good industry; Labor unions; Local transit; Luggage industry; Logging; Medical supplies industry; Medicaid; Motor vehicle industry; Metal trade; Meat industry and trade; Military vehicle industry; Medical instruments and apparatus industry; Management; Measuring instruments; Natural gas pipelines; Notions (Merchandise); Newspaper publishing; Navigation equipment industry; National security; Office management; Office equipment and supplies; Petroleum refineries; Photographic industry; Paper folding (Graphic design); Public utilities; Paper products industry; Political participation; Plastics industry and trade; Pharmaceutical industry; Paint industry and trade; Public administration; Public opinion polls; Paper bag industry; Retail trade; Rug and carpet industry; Railroads; Rubber industry and trade; Railroad equipment industry; Roller bearings; Security systems industry; Service industries; Social security; Shipment of goods; Sanitary supply industry; Soybean industry; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses; Transportation equipment industry.; Telecommunication.; Trucking industry.; Trucks--Design and construction.; Textile industry.; Trade associations.; Tobacco industry.; Universities and colleges.; Vocational education.; Wood products.; Welding equipment industry.; Woolen goods industry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents); Publications (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this Collection:
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 1: Boxes 1-22
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 2: Boxes 23-44
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 3: Boxes 45-66 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 5: Boxes 89-110
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 6: Boxes 111-121
Related Collections:
5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents
5583/2: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3
5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications
5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5
5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6
5956: Archives Organization File Additional records
CONTAINER LIST
- Box: 67, Folder: 1 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Hewitt Associates, Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    By Hewitt Associates. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: New Techniques For Analyzing Deferred Profit Sharing Plans, Publication (Box 67, Folder 1)
    By Thomas E. Wood. Based on a talk at the 1965 Annual Meeting of the Council of Profit Sharing Industries, and is reprinted from Profit Sharing, a publication of the Council. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 2 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Labor Efficiency in Good Times and Bad, Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
    By N. I. Stone. Address before the Plant Executives' Division, October 30th. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Behind the "Seams": Hickey-Freeman Customized Clothes, Publication (Box 67, Folder 2)
    By Hickey-Freeman Company. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 3 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Still Forgotten in 1950 - The High School Teacher of the City of New York, Publication (Box 67, Folder 3)
    By High School Teachers Association of New York City, Inc. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 4 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The Role of Public Relations in Industry, Publication (Box 67, Folder 4)
    By John W. Hill. Presented to employees at the Annual Staff Conference on October 30. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 5 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: 1979 Hitachi Products, Publication (Box 67, Folder 5)
    By Hitachi America. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 6 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Holley Aircraft Carbuertors: The Whole Story in Pictures, Publication (Box 67, Folder 6)
    By Holley Aircraft Carburetor Company. First Edition. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 7 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Retirement Annuity Plan for Employees of Hooker Electrochemical Company Effective October 1, 1946, Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    By Hooker Electrochemical Company. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: A Tribute to Horace Willard Hooker, Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    By Hooker Electrochemical Company. Special edition of Hooker Gas. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Harry Mix Hooker, Publication (Box 67, Folder 7)
    By Hooker Electrochemical Company. Biographical data. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 8 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Regulations, Publication (Box 67, Folder 8)
    By Hooker Mutual Benefit Association. Organized November 26. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 9 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: A Community Program, Publication (Box 67, Folder 9)
    By Thomas J. Morton, Jr.. Address delivered at 40th Annual Convention of the National Metal Trades Association. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 10 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: The HORMEL Annual Wage Wage Incentive and Joint Earnings Plans, Publication (Box 67, Folder 10)
    By Jay C. Hormel. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The HORMEL Annual Wage Wage Incentive and Joint Earnings Plans, Publication (Box 67, Folder 10)
    By Geo. A. Horme & Co. Copy 2. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: The Hormel Employees' Profit-Sharing Trust: An Explanation For, Publication (Box 67, Folder 10)
    By Geo. A. Horme & Co. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: The Hormel Employees' Profit-Sharing Trust: An Explanation For, Publication (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Item 5: The HORMEL Annual Wage Wage Incentive and Joint Earning Plans, Publication (Box 67, Folder 10)
    By Jay C. Hormel. Copy 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Mr. Sherman's talk at Cincinnati, Publication (Box 67, Folder 10)
    By Sherman. October 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: 52 Pay Checks A Year, Publication (Box 67, Folder 10)
    By Oliver F. Fink. Newspaper excerpt; paper unknown, casually referred to as "Pictures,". Item is in English.
  - Item 8: How one industrial plan is helping America, Publication (Box 67, Folder 10)
    By Geo. A. Horme & Co. Reprinted from "Factory Management and Maintenance," August. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 11 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Here at Horne's, Publication (Box 67, Folder 11)
    By Joseph Horne Company. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Retirement Income Plan Indenture between Joseph Horne Co. and The Union National Bank Of Pittsburgh, Publication (Box 67, Folder 11)
    By Joseph Horne Company. Originally dated January 31, 1944, most recently revised to January, 1950. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Group Life Insurance Plan for Employees of the Joseph Horne Co, Publication (Box 67, Folder 11)
    By Joseph Horne Company. January 31. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Pension Plan for employees of the Joseph Horne Co, Publication (Box 67, Folder 11)
    By Joseph Horne Company. First Edition: January 31, 1944; Second Edition - January 31, 1945. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 12 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Program of Supervisory Conferences, Publication (Box 67, Folder 12)
    By Hotpoint. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 13 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Hotpoint Security Plan, Publication (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Item 2: Text of The Employee Introduction Program For Salary Employees, Publication (Box 67, Folder 13)
- Box: 67, Folder: 14 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: By-Laws of Hotel Association of New York City, Inc., Publication (Box 67, Folder 14)
    By Hotel Association of New York City, Inc. April 1. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 15 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: We're right in the middle of everything you do, Publication (Box 67, Folder 15)
    By Howe Richardson Scale Company. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: X-Actron II The Platform Scale Programmed For Profit., Publication (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Item 3: Profit Improvement in Valve Bagging: Howe Richardson's consulting services would like to help you put profits where they belong, Publication (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Item 4: Confidence in weighing: Condensed Catalog No. 7200B, Publication (Box 67, Folder 15)
- Box: 67, Folder: 16 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: The Mining and Preparation of D&H Anthracite, Publication (Box 67, Folder 16)
    By Hudson Coal Company. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 17 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Personnel Forms, Publication (Box 67, Folder 17)
    By Hudson Motor Car Company. Folder of various blank documents and records. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Hudson Motor Car Company Reference Manual for Management and Management Representatives, Publication (Box 67, Folder 17)
    By Hudson Motor Car Company. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Includes sections on personnel policy, safety, and labor legislation, Publication (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Item 4: Supervisor's Reference Manual for Management and Management Representatives, Publication (Box 67, Folder 17)
    By Hudson Motor Car Company. Includes sections on payroll, safety, and social security. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 18 (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Textbook in Methods Of Instruction, Publication (Box 67, Folder 18)
    By Leonard C. Silvern. Field Engineering Department Technical Training. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 19 (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Methods of Training First-Line Supervisors Using Teaching Machine Technology, Publication (Box 67, Folder 19)
    By Hughes Aircraft Company. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: A Systems Approach Utilizing General-Purpose And Special-Purpose Teaching Machines, Publication (Box 67, Folder 19)
- Box: 67, Folder: 20 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Supervisor's Manual, Publication (Box 67, Folder 20)
    By Humble Oil and Refining. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: New Employee Orientation Program Supervisors' guide, Publication (Box 67, Folder 20)
- Box: 67, Folder: 21 (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Materials For Presenting Company Information To Employees, Publication (Box 67, Folder 21)
    By Personnel Development Section Employee Relations Department. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 22 (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: A guide to your Employee Benefits, Publication (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Item 2: Report of Foremanship Conference, Publication (Box 67, Folder 22)
    By Bureau of Industrial Teacher-Training. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Humble Annuity & Thrift Plan, Publication (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Item 4: Benefit Plan For Employees And Annuitants of Humble Oil & Refining Company, Publication (Box 67, Folder 22)
- Box: 67, Folder: 23 (Box 67, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Charter and By- Laws of The Houston Homestead and Loan Association, Publication (Box 67, Folder 23)
    By Houston Homestead and Loan Association. Item is in English.
- Box: 67, Folder: 24 (Box 67, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: "From Youth to Age", Publication (Box 67, Folder 24)
    By F. C. Huyck & Sons. Item is in English.
- Box: 68, Folder: 1 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Forward 601296, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
    By Hydro-Electric Power Commission of Ontario. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Training Handbook, Publication (Box 68, Folder 1)
    By N. B Corbett. Item is in English.
- Box: 68, Folder: 2 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Information from ICI Americas, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
    By ICI United States Inc. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Who Are We & What Do We Make, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
    By ICI Americas Inc.. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: ICI Americas Inc., Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Pursue your career at ICI United States, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: who are we & what do we make, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: ICI Americas Inc., Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Who are we & what do we make?, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Construction begins on $25 million Biomed Research Lab expansion, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
    By ICI United States Inc. Management briefs August. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Personnel News: Treasurer's Deparment Bulletin, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
    By R. J. Reilly. November 10. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Personnel News: Pharmaceuticals Group Administrative Services Bulletin Regulatory Affairs Department, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
    By A. J. Milbauer. November 17. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Life Insurance, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: Deferred Compensation Plan, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 13: ICI Magazine September 1976, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
    By ICI United States Inc. Vol. 54 No. 438. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: ICI United States Inc., Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 15: Select a career one best for you., Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 16: Employment History Form, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 17: Pension Plan, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 18: General Information - Wilmington, Delaware, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 19: New Hires Relocation Policy, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 20: Purchasing A Home, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Item 21: Organization Manual Roster: Officers & Directors, Publication (Box 68, Folder 2)